Register of the Panamanian Subject Collection, 1951-1999
Hoover Institution Archives
Panamanian Subject Collection,
1951-1999
XX806
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize box (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, election campaign literature, bulletins, reports, and studies, relating primarily to political conditions and elections in Panama, the Panama Canal, relations between Panama and the United States, and the American invasion of Panama in 1989.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Panama--Politics and government.; Elections--Panama.; Panama Canal.; Panama--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Panama.; Panama--History--American Invasion, 1989.; United States--Foreign relations.; Panama.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1951-1994. (Box No. 1.)
  Reports, pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues and memorandum. Arranged alphabetically by subject
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1985-1989. (Box No. 2.)
  Serial issues, pamphlets and posters
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received since December 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1951-1994
  - General. Serial issues, pamphlets and leaflets, largely concerning political and economic conditions, relations with the United States and controversies surrounding the Panama Canal, 1951-1990. Includes publications from political parties, student and peasant groups, and material on the rule of Manuel Noriega (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Elections
    - 1984. Report (Folder 3)
    - 1985. Reports (Folder 4)
    - 1994. Newsletter about women candidates (Folder 5)
  - United States. Serial issue, memorandum and pamphlets, relating primarily to relations with the United States, American military activity and controversies surrounding the Panama Canal, 1964-1990. Includes material from the United States Army subsequent to the American invasion of Panama in 1989 (Folder 6)
  - Universities. Pamphlets concerning educational issues and student movements, 1988-1989 (Folder 7)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1985-1989 (Box No. 2)
  Serial issues, pamphlets and posters, largely concerning political conditions and religious issues. Includes material from evangelical organizations and the Partido del Pueblo